Mike MacCana

Front end, back end, cloud infrastructure.

Founding, bootstrapping, hiring, troubleshooting.

+44 7547 004474

mike.maccana@gmail.com

https://mikemaccana.com

Summary

Mike has 22 years' experience in tech, including as a founder, product manager, team lead and engineer with

current skills across the entire stack. He has worked for giants including Google, Microsoft and Red Hat, and

founded, grew and sold startups. He is available to work anywhere in the world. Top 0.13% StackOverflow.

GitHub Arctic Code Vault 2020.

Experience and Abilities

High level: product management, talent acquisition, technical marketing, running developer events, public

speaking, technical leadership, mentoring.

Technical infrastructure: deep Linux (RHEL contributor), deep AWS and Serverless (have developed the largest

Serverless app in the world and have code in the GAE SDK), AWS (contributed to the original node AWS SDK),

CloudInit (have written CloudInit generators), nginx, systemd, messaging middleware, automation of large scale

systems nearly all automation systems, powershell, bash, XML (creator of docx module for python)

Web technologies: node.js (author of most popular node deployment guide on Google), TypeScript, Python,

scraping (Cheerio, JSDOM, puppeteer), data binding (Svelte, Vue, React), webextensions, HTTP

(HTTPS/Brotli/HTTP2 etc. creator of various eslint plugins, exposure to most other languages.

UX and user stories: front end JavaScript (ES2021), CSS grid, flex, variables and calc,

animation, SCSS, snap.svg, etc.

Career

Feb 2020 to Present

# Lead Engineer, Daisie

Responsible for technical decision making and developer velocity for team of six and 160,000 users. • Resolved ElasticSearch issues to provide deterministic search results. • Migrated chat backend users in 6 weeks with no downtime. • Introduced first revenue generating feature (live hosted workshops) with protype in 1 weekend and final version in 3 months. • Sped CI times from up to 42 minutes to 2-3 minutes. • Automated manual AWS tasks. •Mentored other developers and determined engineering processes.

## Founder, CertSimple, London UK

Built the industry's fastest platform to verify websites. Went from 0 to 22K GBP a month. • Technologies: node.js, ractive.JS, in-depth HTTPS. webcrypto, HTML5 clipboard, web components, cheerio, puppeteer. Also fundraising, acquiring mentors, negotiating with suppliers, etc. CertSimple was sold to ExpeditedSSL in Jan 2020.

# Contract developer, Make Us Proud

Built the launch site for the new Microsoft Surface and worked on payments and subscription infrastructure for online learning startup. • Technologies: SCSS, Stripe, node.js

#### Tech Lead, Sandpit Lab, London UK

Ran a team of engineers creating an app to provide alerts of major events 40 minutes before BBC and Sky had published stories on them. • Language: JavaScript (both frontend JavaScript and node.js) • Technologies: Vanilla JS, Twitter API, Datasift, MongoDB/Mongoose, ractive,js, gulp, SASS, highcharts, various custom-built libraries.

Feb 2015 to Dec 2019

Oct 2014 - Feb 2015

Apr 2014 to Oct 2014

Jul 2013 - Mar 2014

### Founder, Firework, London UK

Designed and developed software to allow software to be deployed into cloud environments directly from GitHub. • Language: JavaScript (both frontend JavaScript and node.js) • Technologies: GitHub API, AWS SDK, ractive.JS, MongoDB, Express, Agave.JS, Docker Remote API, CoreOS, systemd

#### Apr 2012 - Jul 2013

#### Senior Developer, Bazaarvoice, London & Austin TX

Wrote full-stack (UI to backend) code and shared libraries for popular Facebook apps used by worldwide retailers and brands including Adobe, Nikon, and Samsung. • Designed and built realtime EC2 deployment tools handling complex tasks including continuous integration, load balancing, and auto-scaling with simple minimal web UI, used for thousands of instances per month. • Language: Python, JavaScript • Technologies: Tornado, Node.JS, ES5 shim, Facebook API, Instagram API, RabbitMQ, jQuery, AWS lib, Agave.JS

## Engineer Creative Lab, Google

Jan 2011 - Mar 2012

Working on pro moment and complex Django Nonrel projects (Google Engage and Getting American Business Online) with Google CEO attention. Engage is the largest Google App Engine app in existence and spans 33 countries. Getting X Business Online (X being a market) is a worldwide programme to lower national levels of businesses that don't have an online presence.

Worked on smaller, faster projects including multi-national retail training apps for Android 4 Ice Cream Sandwich launch, Google 10 Years in Germany, and YouTube WorldView. • Language: Python, JavaScript (ES5) • Technologies: Django, Google App Engine, Django NonRel, ElementTree, JQuery, Cake JS, underscore JS, Twitter Bootstrap, wrote own custom libraries for YouTube, OAuth2, AppEngine REST and many more.

Oct-2010- Jan 2011

# Founder, I'm Everyone

Built complete backend & frontend web-based problem and discussion app (imeveryone.com). • Realtime (COMET / AJAX push / async etc) web app based on Tornado framework, MongoDB NoSQL database, and REST, handling and filtering user-generated-content. • Language: Python, JavaScript • Technologies: tornado MVC, pymongo, configobj, queue, threading, akismet, pyfilter, jQuery, jQuery UI, FQL (Facebook Query Language), many more.

#### Aug 2009- Oct 2010

# Low Latency Trading Engineer, Credit Suisse

Automated the build and testing process of co-located index arbitrage servers receiving data feeds and trading with 12 separate exchanges on hundreds of sockets per host • Made tools to test, troubleshoot, and configure low latency / high frequency trading infrastructure, interfacing with firmware, schedulers, network devices, and applications. • Language: Python, Systemtap, IronPython (.net) • Technologies: icmplib, paramiko, xlwt, RHEL MRG (message / realtime / grid) APIs, various custom-created libraries implementing CS business logic and tests

# Linux Architect, Man Group, London

Nov 2008 - Aug 2009

Designed the server and application platform for the world largest listed hedge fund • Language: Python • Technologies: rpm and yum libraries, various custom-created Man libraries, django, PyOFC. Python itself implementing as kickstart post and preinstall scripts. • Was final technical point of call for Linux within Man Group beyond 10 regular support staff • Worked closely with algorithmic trading developers • Emphasis on kernel level performance tuning, high availability, automation, and reporting • Built automated tools for reporting of asset data, performance, machine and user account provisioning • Language: Python • Technologies: RHN Satellite API, XLWT API, SOAP • Integrated major line of business apps on Linux and Unix with Active Directory infrastructure

Jun 2006 - Sep 2008

#### Linux and Automation Technical Specialist, IBM GS Melbourne

Created staff privilege revalidation used for 75,000 staff accounts at an IBM GS customer • Technologies: Python LDAP, LXML / xpath, expect, various custom config parsers, smtplib • Designed the OS build used on IBM-GS managed Linux hosts for one of IBM's top 5 worldwide clients. • Led team of 6 engineers to build Telstra Enterprise Data Warehouse (grid computing environment) including automating deploy process on Blade hardware, and coordinating with datacenter cabling, network, DBA and app teams • Designed, implemented, troubleshot and upgraded VMware solutions for IBM customers including telecoms, public utilities and government departments.

### Trainer, Red Hat Asia Pacific

May 2003 - Nov 2005

Taught large-scale n-tier solution design and clustering for Red Hat Certified Architect curricula. • Trained and certified nearly 500 Red Hat Certified Engineers and Architects across Asia Pacific. • Designed, installed, configured, troubleshot, performance tuned, and clustered networking services in front of an audience on a daily basis. • Improved product being delivered by contributing to Red Hat's Rapid Track RHCE courseware and Red Hat Enterprise Linux itself. • Language: Python • Technologies: Anaconda, libvirt, other Red Hat custom libraries.

# Technical Specialist, Cybersource, Melbourne

May 1999 - May 2003

Designed and built a Linux-based mail/web/file/antivirus appliance. The Small Business Linux Server was first-to-market with more functionality than its rivals. • Language: Perl • Technologies: webmin modules and parsers to work with common Linux network services • Wrote, instructed and maintained a 5-day Red Hat Linux based network administration course. Clients included largest Australian telecom company (Telstra) and Melbourne University. The course rights were sold to a third party and the course is taught regularly years later. • Worked up from a desktop support role to the head of a 3-person team running mail, DNS, and SMB servers as well as two NAT firewalls for an Asia-wide PR company.

#### Education

# Certificate I in Business Management, Box Hill Institute

Tertiary level studies completed after hours while at grammar (secondary) school

# Certifications

• 2008 certified LEAN professional • 2008 Certified Scrum Master • 2002 RHCX (ability to train and certify others as Red Hat Certified Architects / RHCE / RHCT). RHCX ID 807202912505514 • 1999 MCSE - MCP ID: 1463454 • 1997 MindShop Excellence Programme (combined TQM / Kaizen / project management) • 1997 Young Achievers Business Alive

# Visas and Relocation

Mike possesses both an EU passport (Ireland), and is also an Australian citizen (eligible for <u>E-3 specialty</u> occupation visa for the US). He is happy to relocate for the right role.